outsideonline.com 2008-05-16

# The Away Network: Privacy Policy

---  
About Us |    **|**    | [Advertise with Us](mailto:advertising@away.com) |    **|**    | Feedback |    **|**    | Jobs |    **|**    | Terms of Use |    **|**    | Privacy  
Effective: December 2006

This Privacy Policy describes the principles and practices that apply to personal information collected from users of our services ("you") on the Web sites at which this policy is posted (the "Site"), including www.away.com (but not including third party pages hosted at that URL). This policy also applies to information you submit to us by telephone or through e-mail communications, or in interviews, surveys, sweepstakes, contests, or raffles. 

## Your California Privacy Rights

Under California Law, California residents have the right to request in writing from businesses with whom they have an established business relationship, (1) a list of the categories of personal information, such as name, address, e-mail address, and the type of services provided to the customer, that a business has disclosed to third parties (including affiliates that are separate legal entities) during the immediately preceding calendar year for the third parties' direct marketing purposes, and (2) the names and addresses of all such third parties. To request the above information, please write to us at: Privacy Coordinator, The Away Network, 1001 G Street, NW, Suite 725 W, Washington, DC 20001, with a reference to California Disclosure Information. 

We will respond to such written requests within 30 days following receipt at the mailing address stated above. If we receive your request at a different mailing address, we will respond within a reasonable period of time, but not to exceed 150 days from the date received. Please note that we are only required to respond to each customer once per calendar year. 

The remainder of this policy describes our personal information handling practices in detail.

## Consent

BY SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US, AND/OR BY USING OUR SITE, YOU AGREE THAT WE MAY COLLECT, USE AND DISCLOSE SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND AS PERMITTED OR REQUIRED BY LAW. 

If you do not agree with these terms, do not provide any personal information to us. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, or if you choose not to provide us with any required personal information, we may not be able to provide you with products or services that can be offered on our Site only if we have access to certain personal information.

## Minors

Minors (as defined under the laws of their jurisdiction or residence) are not eligible to register for, use, or purchase products or Services available on the Away Network Web sites. We do not knowingly collect personal information from any Minor, and will not use this information if we discover that it has been provided by a Minor.

## Personal and Demographic Data Collected by The Away Network

When you register on the Site, we ask for your name, email address, postal code, year of birth, gender, country of residence, and in some instances information pertaining to your preferred departure airport and personal interests. (You can access and update this information by accessing the "Update My Account" Web page. If you have difficulty reaching this page, please visit our "Customer Feedback" Web page.) 

During or after registration, or in connection with other interactive features such as entering a contest or promotion, The Away Network may also ask for other personal information, such as your personal interests (including favorite activity and destination), address, birth date, occupation, and income range. The Away Network might collect this information through personal interest forms, surveys, or contests. We also ask whether you want to receive emails from us or special offers from partners. See the section on "Sharing of Data" for further detail.

You can still use the Site without providing personal information, but you will not be able to take advantage of many of our personalized services.

## Public Forums & Reviews 

The Away Network makes message boards and forums available to its members, as well as allowing you to submit reviews about your travel experiences or about travel products. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information in such a forum.

## Cookies and I.P. Addresses 

As part of offering you a valuable service, The Away Network uses cookies or "pixel tags" to provide personalized services and content, as well as to collect "Session Data." A cookie or "pixel tag" is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. A cookie is set when you browse our site. You can set your browser to refuse cookies, but your user experience at The Away Network will be significantly limited if you do so. "Session Data" includes such information as, the type of Internet browser and operating system an individual uses, the domain name of the site from which the individual came, the date, time and duration of the visit, number of visits, average time spent on the individual's site, pages viewed, domain name of the individual, and number of cookies accumulated.

We use cookies to: (1) customize your online experience; (2) enable you to obtain access to our member-only Web pages without having to retype your login name and password; (3) allow us to offer personalized services to you; and (4) calculate the number of people who visit an Away Network Web site (or a certain Web page) to allow us to provide better service in the future. Unless you register, we cannot identify you other than through the information stored in the cookie. 

## Sharing Of Data 

  * Select Partners and Affiliates: The Away Network shares your personal information with third parties only with your express permission, or as otherwise disclosed in this privacy policy. For example, Away Network may share your information with a third party when, if in acting on a third party promotion described in an e-mail we have sent or on our Site, you provide additional personal information (such as age, income range, activity interests, etc.) you consent to that information being shared with the designated partner. Additionally, if a contest is sponsored by or together with any of The Away Network's strategic partners, we may share information with that sponsor. By entering the contest you are consenting to our sponsor receiving the information you provide. That partner will have its own privacy policy that governs its use of the information you provide.
  * Third Party Web sites on "Away" URL: The Away Network hosts and maintains a separate Web site on the away.com URL, the Outside Online Web site (which is accessible from outside.away.com, www.outsideonline.com, and www.outsidemag.com). All information collected by The Away Network on Outside Online is subject to this privacy policy. Information collected on the Outside Online may be shared with Mariah Media Inc., the publisher of Outside Magazine.
  * HistoricTraveler.com: If you provide any personal information on HistoricTraveler.com (which is a site hosted and maintained by The Away Network) this information may be shared with PRIMEDIA Inc., a partner of The Away Network. The HistoricTraveler.com Site has its own privacy policy and any information collected on the HistoricTraveler.com Site is governed by its privacy policy. 
  * Co-branded Sites that Offer Merchandise: The Away Network may have links to the Web sites of other entities to allow you to purchase merchandise. These Web sites may look similar to The Away Network, but are run by separate entities with whom The Away Network has partnered (look in your browser bar to determine if you are still on an Away Network Web site, located at away.com). The Away Network receives a commission for any purchases you make on partner sites. To help calculate these commissions, The Away Network sends a tracking number to the partners. We do not provide personal information to our merchandise partners (except with your permission or as otherwise mentioned herein). Our merchandise partners provide us with aggregate purchase data, no individual purchase data is disclosed. Each partner site has its own privacy policy on gathering information from you. You may wish to check this policy before giving out personal information. The Away Network does not control how a partner uses information gathered on its site. 
  * AdventurousTraveler.com: The Away Network offers books, maps, and other products through the AdventurousTraveler.com (http://atb.away.com) Web site which Away hosts and maintains. Amazon.com provides the fulfillment of all orders placed on AdventurousTraveler.com and has its own privacy policy governing purchase transactions made on its Web site.
  * Aggregated Data: The Away Network will provide aggregate, anonymous information (e.g. "55% of our members enjoy hiking") to advertisers and third parties. Such aggregate data cannot be linked to any one person. 
  * Required Disclosure: The Away Network will disclose personal information when required to by law enforcement or other appropriate governmental authorities, or if the personal information is pertinent in a legal proceeding or court action. 
  * Business Transfers: As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy Web sites or other assets. In such transactions, customer information is usually one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the event that Mariah Media or The Away Network merges with or sells all or substantially all of its assets to another company, customer information collected on The Away Network Web sites may be one of the transferred assets.

## Advertising Services 

Third parties advertise on our Site, and we also contract with third parties to serve ads across the Internet. These third parties may serve ads about our products or services, or third party products or services in which, based on your Session Data, we or our business partners believe you may be interested. 

While we may share Session Data with third parties to help facilitate the serving of these ads, we do not share any personal information about you unless you give us permission to do so, separate from any permission you provide during the Member registration process. These third parties may seek to use cookies and pixel tags, including those collected on our Site, to track Session Data about the ads you have seen and types of things in which you appear interested. These third parties may also use combined information about your visits to our Site and other sites in order to provide advertisements about related goods and services that may be of interest to you. 

When you click on a third party advertisers' link from our Site, you will be taken off of our Site and will enter the third party's site. We are not responsible for such third party's sites. You should carefully review the privacy statements of any other site you visit, because those privacy statements will apply to your visit to that site, and may be very different from our policy.

## Email 

From time to time we may provide special offers on this Site, or may send special email offers about our products and services. Or, if you elected to receive them, those of selected partners or our affiliated companies. The Away Network will not send you any email that you do not wish to receive. If you wish to receive newsletters and special offers by email from The Away Network, selected partners, or our affiliated companies, you can visit the ["Email Subscriptions"](http://away.com/pvt/subscriptions.tcl) Web page. If at any time you wish to unsubscribe from any of The Away Network's email products, either click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of these communications or visit the ["Email Subscriptions"](http://away.com/pvt/subscriptions.tcl) Web page and deselect the email products that you no longer wish to receive. To access this Web page, you will need to be logged-in to The Away Network, which may require you to type-in your Away Network password. If you are having difficulty reaching our E-mail Subscriptions page, please access The Away Network's ["Customer Feedback"](http://away.com/feedback/customer_feedback.html) Web page. 

Periodically, The Away Network introduces new email products or improves existing ones. If you are subscribed to an Away Network email product we may provide you with a trial subscription to the new product. You may unsubscribe from any of these products at any time. 

We use an email system that can individually track who opens an email (if you receive the email in HTML format) and who clicks on any link contained in an email. This is personally-identifiable information, which we collect to: 

  1. calculate how many people were interested in particular topics or particular links contained in an email product; and 
  2. provide personalized services that are best suited to your interests 

If you do not wish such information to be collected about you, you should unsubscribe from our emails.

## Security 

The Away Network employs physical, administrative and technical safeguards to help protect the confidentiality and integrity of personal information and to reduce the risk of loss, misuse, unauthorized access disclosure or modification of personal information. 

As a further security precaution, The Away Network asks you to provide a password when you register on our Web sites. You then have the option of storing that password on a cookie set on your computer. This way, you need not type in the password when you again access The Away Network's Web sites.

If the computer you are using is not for your sole use, after you have finished accessing an Away Network Web site, you should click on the [this link](http://away.com/reg/logout.tcl), which will sign you off of the Web site. This action prevents other people from accessing your information. When you want to access member-only areas of The Away Network's Web sites at another time, you will need to sign-in and type-in your password. You will have the option of having your password e-mailed to you if you have forgotten what it is. 

If you choose to contact the Away Network through the Web site, you should be aware that any information transmitted electronically via the World Wide Web might not be secure. The Away Network assumes no liability for the loss of any information that you transmit to us via the World Wide Web. 

In communicating with you, we may send e-mail as unencrypted plain text because we are aware that many users cannot readily process encrypted e-mail. This is done for your convenience, but with the security concern that, if misrouted or intercepted, it could be read more easily than encrypted e-mail.

## Changes in Privacy Policy

As the nature of our business changes, The Away Network may need to change its privacy policy. If the policy is changed, this page will be updated. If there is a material change to this policy we will notify all users who are currently receiving email from The Away Network. 

If you have any questions or suggestions about this privacy policy, please contact privacy@away.com. Alternatively, you can mail The Away Network at: 

Privacy Coordinator  
The Away Network  
1001 G Street, NW  
Suite 725W  
Washington, DC 20001   

Only questions about The Away Network's Privacy Policy should be addressed to the above addresses. Any inquiries sent to these addresses that are not related to the Privacy Policy will not be reviewed. You may address other concerns regarding The Away Network, by visiting the ["Customer Feedback"](http://away.com/feedback/customer_feedback.html) Web page.
